<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bryan FitzGerald on Bryan FitzGerald</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bryan FitzGerald on Bryan FitzGerald</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Bryan FitzGerald</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate Change Guilt</title>
      <link>/project/climate_change_guilt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/climate_change_guilt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Currently Collecting Data&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guilty Participants</title>
      <link>/project/guilty_participant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/guilty_participant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Analyzing the racial attitudes scale as ranging from racial animus to racial liberalism, the current paper examines the emotional foundation for racial liberalism, white guilt, and its relationship to political participation. We start by theorizing that White Americans who recognize their systemic advantage relative to African-Americans as illegitimate, develop feelings of guilt. In an attempt to relieve this negative emotion, racially liberal Whites take action in politics aimed toward racial equality. We draw upon survey data utilizing traditional regression methods and propensity score matching. We find that Whites with stronger feelings of guilt are more likely to participate in various modes of participation ranging from donating to political organizations and attending political meetings to boycotting and boycotting products for political reasons; we find no effects for voting. The results from matching methods provide evidence that white guilt may cause an increase in participation propensity. The paper increases our understanding about how and why dominant group members may assist marginalized communities in pursuit of racial equality in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
